<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-04-19T15:34:55+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">3liasP’s Home Page</title><subtitle>A personal blog and homepage made with GitHub Pages.</subtitle><author><name>3liasP</name></author><entry><title type="html">Jumpstart Your Web Dev Journey with React</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/react/web%20development/javascript/2023/04/17/react1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jumpstart Your Web Dev Journey with React" /><published>2023-04-17T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2023-04-17T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/react/web%20development/javascript/2023/04/17/react1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/react/web%20development/javascript/2023/04/17/react1.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/personal-page/docs/assets/img/dustin-react-min.png&quot; alt=&quot;Dustin trying React JS!&quot; title=&quot;Dustin trying React JS!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the first actual post of “Bytes and Beyond,” a programming blog by 3liasP. In this post, we will briefly dive into the world of React, a popular JavaScript library for building user interfaces. React is widely used by developers and has become an essential tool for web development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;React was first introduced by Facebook in 2011 and has since gained immense popularity. It is known for its simplicity, reusability, and performance. React follows a component-based approach, where the user interface is divided into small, reusable components. Each component can manage its own state, making it easy to build complex user interfaces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the main advantages of using React is that it allows developers to create dynamic and interactive user interfaces quickly. React enables developers to build applications that can update and render efficiently, making it ideal for developing modern web applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;React is widely used in the industry, and many popular websites such as Facebook, Instagram, and Netflix, are built using React. React also has a vast ecosystem of tools and libraries, making it easy for developers to create robust and scalable applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get started with React, you need to have a good understanding of JavaScript and the Document Object Model (DOM). React also relies heavily on HTML and CSS, so a good understanding of these technologies is also crucial. Once you have a good grasp of the fundamentals, you can start learning React by following tutorials and building small applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, React is an essential tool for web development, and its popularity continues to grow. If you are looking to become a web developer or improve your existing skills, learning React is a must. With its simplicity and performance, React makes it easy to build modern and interactive user interfaces.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>3liasP</name></author><category term="React" /><category term="Web Development" /><category term="JavaScript" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hello World, I’m 3liasP</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/introduction/2023/04/16/intro.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hello World, I’m 3liasP" /><published>2023-04-16T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2023-04-16T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/introduction/2023/04/16/intro</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/introduction/2023/04/16/intro.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/docs/assets/img/dustin-hello-min.png&quot; alt=&quot;Dustin on writing his first program!&quot; title=&quot;Dustin on writing his first program!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If did read the introduction, you would already know that I’m a bachelor student studying IT in University Of Turku. In this blog post I will give some insights to my skills as a programmer, what languages I’m most familiar with and why I chose to learn them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Java is arguably the programming language that I’m most familiar with, although at the time of writing this post, I’m also into JavaScript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Java is the chosen programming language for most of my courses. It’s a great choice for learning, because it’s one of the most popular programming languages used for developing desktop and web applications. It is widely used in the development of Android apps and provides extensive libraries for developing robust applications. JavaScript, on the other hand, is the go-to language for web development, enabling developers to create dynamic and interactive web pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also done some work in Python and I’m fairly familiar with it and it’s strengths. Python is a general-purpose language, well-suited for scripting, automation and data analysis. The last two familiar languages for me are C and SQL. I learned C while studying embedded systems at the university. I learned that it was a foundational language for systems programming, providing developers with low-level control over the hardware. That’s also one of the reasons why it’s one the most popular language when it comes to embedded systems. SQL was something I learned while studying the fundamentals of databases. It’s the standard language for working with relational databases, making it a critical skill for any aspiring programmer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As someone with aspirations of becoming a programmer, I understand the importance of keeping up with the latest developments in the field. The programming industry is rapidly growing and evolving, with new languages, frameworks, and tools being developed every day. With a solid foundation in programming languages, I am well-positioned to adapt to these changes and stay ahead of the curve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, I am focusing on web development and embedded systems. Web development involves creating websites, web applications, and other web-based software, while embedded systems are specialized computer systems designed to perform specific tasks. I am excited about the potential of these fields and look forward to exploring them further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this blog, you can expect to read about my experiences as a student and programmer, my thoughts on programming languages and frameworks and my insights into the future of the field. I will also be sharing tutorials, code snippets, and other resources that I find helpful and informative. Thank you for joining me on this journey, and I hope you find my blog informative and engaging.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>3liasP</name></author><category term="Introduction" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>